《尖峰时刻》
Don't move.
不要动
I'm in position, move in.
我抓到他了,进来吧
Where is Juntao?
钟涛在哪里?
Juntao? He is everywhere.
钟涛无所不在
You want a piece of me?
你想跟我斗吗?
Don't move!
不要动
Shoot me!
开枪呀
尽管开枪呀
Sang got away.
姓桑的跑了
Forgive me, Consul Han.
恕我直言,韩领事
I believe we can ill afford to lose men of your high character.
失去你这种正人君子是我们的损失
And speaking as a friend who's fought side by side with you
作为朋友,我跟你并肩作战
for 15 years...
整整十五年...
I will miss the unshakable support you've given the Royal Hong Kong Police.
我会想念你对香港皇家警署坚定的支持
On behalf of all Brits
我谨代表所有
who have ever carried the shield in Hong Kong
香港皇家警察向你说
we shall miss you.
我们会想念你
And we wish you happiness
祝你愉快
as you take up your new post in the United States.
希望你在美国的新职一切顺利
Ladies and gentlemen, Consul Han.
各位女士先生,韩领事
Thank you, Thomas.
谢谢你,汤玛斯
Now, you know,
你们知道
Thomas is not going to make this evening easy.
汤玛斯这一席话让我很感动
Excuse me.
对不起
Commander Griffin
葛芬指挥官
I am pleased to leave you and Hong Kong with a special gift tonight.
我为你和香港留下一份大礼
Earlier, Detective Inspector Lee and his special task force
稍早李探长率领飞虎队
have once and for all crushed the Juntao criminal organization
将钟涛犯罪集团一网打尽
and reclaimed artifacts from 5000 years of China's heritage
寻获中国五千年来的无价之宝
This is the kind of legacy I dreamt about.
这是我长久以来的心愿
Hong Kong forever
香港万岁
To Hong Kong, forever
愿香港永远辉煌
Soo Yung.
素洋
Why didn't you tell me you weren't going with us?
你怎么没说你不跟我们去?
I was trying to find the right time.
我一直在找机会说
When? After I left?
几时?等我走了?
Soo Yung, I'll miss you very much.
素洋,我会很想你的
You're my best student!
你是我最好的徒弟
Your mother would've been proud.
你母亲会很骄傲
Will you practice your kicks and eye gouges?
你会继续练习踢腿和眼工吗?
I don't like America.
我觉得美国不适合我
I won't have any friend in America.
我也没有美国的朋友
Everything will be O.K. I promise.
一切都会顺利的,我保证
This is for you.
你一定最受欢迎
Thank you.
谢谢
Don't worry.
不要担心
America is a very friendly place.
美国是一个很友好的地方
Stupid fool, get out of my way!
蠢猪,给我让开
Man, are you crazy?
你疯了吗?
Shoot!
该死
You moron!
你这笨蛋
Clive, what's up, man?
克莱夫,怎么样?
You're late.
你迟到了
I'm late? Yeah, you're late.
我迟到? 对,你迟到了
I've been waiting inside for an hour.
我在车上等了一个钟头
I was in the diner.
我在餐厅里面
I told you, "the back of the diner."
我说到餐厅后面
You thought I'd do this up front?
你认为我会在前台干这个吗?
Are you crazy? I'll get busted.
我会坐牢的
I was in the diner, you weren't.
我在餐厅,你没来
I said... It don't even matter.
我说过...算了
I'm late, you late, it don't matter. Let's do this.
算我没说,办正事吧
What's that? Put that gun away.
干嘛?快收起来
How many people you killed this year?
你想杀人吗?
Stop it. Come on, let's do it.
别耍狠,办正事吧
Don't be late again.
下次别迟到
I ain't going to be late. Come on.
不会啦,快点吧
That's tight. That's beautiful. That's nice.
酷毙了,太正点了
What's that? That's C-4.
这是什么? 塑胶炸药
That's C-4? That's C-4.
就是这玩意? 没错
Oh, shit!
妈的
What's the problem?
怎么了?
Ain't no problem. I been looking everywhere for this shit.
没事,我一直在找这玩意
How the hell you find some C-4?
你竟然弄到手了?
You don't know how you're making me feel.
我太高兴了
The Iraqis can't even get this shit
连海珊都弄不到
Who'd you get this from?
你从哪儿弄来的?
That's a hot ticket.
这是抢手货
You don't know how happy you made me.
我太高兴了
You got what I want. I'll get what you want. Let me get that money.
你手上有货,我去拿钱
Step away from the car.
从车旁走开
Officers. Hands above your heads.
警察先生 把手放在头上
What's wrong, officers?
有什么事吗? 乖乖照办
Just do it. No problem here. Why mess with us?
没问题,别找我们的碴
Take it easy, buddy! You don't want to do that.
别乱来,不要乱来
Yes, I do!
我要宰了他
No, he don't. He's just playing!
不会的,他是开玩笑
No, I ain't playing!
我不是开玩笑
Yes, he is, officer!
他在开玩笑
Drop the gun!
把枪放下
He's my cousin. We're talking.
他是我表哥,我们在聊天
Get back in the car and leave.
你们先走吧
We can't do that, buddy!
办不到
I'm going to blow his head all over the parking lot!
我要把他的脑袋轰掉
Get in the car and buy some doughnuts.
去吃甜甜圈吧
See what you did? You made him mad. Let me talk to him.
他抓狂了,让我劝劝他
Don't move!
别动
Everything cool now. He down, the gun down.
没事了,他被我撂倒
Now get back in the car and leave.
请你们快走吧
Put your hands on your head!
手放在头上
Officer, everything cool, officer.
警察先生,没事了
Do it now!
快点
Didn't I tell you to get in the car?
谁叫你们不听话
Stop it! I got C-4 in the trunk!
别开枪,车上有炸药
Clive... guess what, man?
克莱夫,猜怎么着?
I forgot to tell you. I'm LAPD.
我忘了说,我是洛城警探
You under arrest.
你被捕了
(洛杉矶 中国领事馆)
Soo Yung, come on. We're going to be late.
快一点,要迟到了
Let's go.
走吧
Excuse me.
对不起
Telephone. China.
您的电话,大陆打来的
Soo Yung.
素洋
I love you. Have a nice day.
我爱你,乖乖上学去
Will you be home after school?
我放学你会在家吗?
No. I am going to pick you up myself.
不会,我要去接你
Good-bye.
再见
Hello, this is Han. Hello?
喂,我是韩...喂?
When you walk by every night
当你每晚潇洒地走过来
talking sweet and looking fine.
谈吐迷人,风度翩翩
I get kind of hectic inside.
是我的梦中情人
Baby, I'm so into you
为你深深着迷
Darling, if you only knew
当你看着我时
all the things that flow through my mind
我的心就像小鹿乱撞
Is there a problem officer?
有问题吗,警官?
No problem. Just rush hour.
没问题,只是尖峰时刻
Security's in place?
保全都没问题吧?
You're sure the exhibits will be ready this weekend?
这周末能如期展出吗?
Yes, sir. Your opening remarks are scheduled for 7:30.
可以,七点半开幕
Excuse me, Consul Han...
对不起,韩领事
I'm Warren Russ with the Federal Bureau of Investigation
我是联邦调查局的罗华伦
This is Agent Whitney. We need to speak with you in private, sir.
这是魏干员,我们私下谈谈
Excuse me.
失陪
I know this is a difficult time for you, consul...
我知道你很难过
but I want you to know, we'll get your daughter back.
但我们一定会找回令嫒
Will you get her back alive?
她能活着回来吗?
We have the best agents in the world in this house and on those streets.
最优秀的干员正在侦办此案
I would like one of my people to help.
我想找别人帮忙
Let me assure you, Consul,
请放心,领事
the FBI considers this a top priority.
FBI认为这是重大案件
We have plenty of people on the case.
我们会出动全力
Mr. Russ, I am not an American.
我不是美国人
My daughter, she is not an American.
我女儿也不是美国人
I understand that, sir, but...
我知道
He's already on a plane.
他已经搭机赶来
I trust you will treat him with the same courtesy as you have shown me.
希望他也能受到相同的礼遇
Yes, sir.
是的
Ten people jumped out.
对方有十个
I started slapping and throwing them everywhere.
都被我打得落花流水
Then two stupid cops came and messed everything up.
结果都那两个笨警察搞砸
I had to save their life. It might be in the paper...
我救了他们,可能会上报
I saved their life and then
我救了他们的命
I start running and trying to get the bomb...
我奋不顾身去追炸药...
I can't believe you went without me.
你怎么不找我支援?
I'll talk to y'all later.
稍候我会告诉你所有的
I'll tell you the best part after work.
等我下班再讲最精采的部分
This is why nobody will work with you.
没人敢跟你合作
Why you're the only cop in the department without a partner
难怪只有你没有搭档
Johnson, look, first of all:
强森,第一点
If you want to go on a date, you'll have to wait on the list
你想跟我约会就得排队
like every other woman.
像别的女人一样
And second of all: I work alone.
我一向单枪匹马
I don't want no partner. Don't need no partner.
用不着搭档,也不想有搭档
And I'll never have a partner.
也从未有搭档
Did Kojak have a partner?
光头神探有搭档吗?
The fat guy.
他的胖助手
He wasn't never with him. Did Columbo have a partner?
他没办案,哥伦坡也没搭档
Captain Diel ordered me to go with you
戴尔队长命令我协助你
because you needed bomb squad backup.
因为你要爆破小组支援
But once again, you screwed me and you screwed yourself.
把我惹毛对你没好处
Look, Johnson, it's dangerous out there.
外面很危险
It's safer for you to be here behind the desk.
坐办公桌比较安全
We were supposed to be on the same team.
你要有团队精神
Team? Johnson, this is the LAPD.
我们是洛城警探
We the most hated cops in the free world.
自由世界最顾人怨的警察
My own mama ashamed of me. She tell everybody I'm a drug dealer.
我妈觉得丢脸,说我是毒贩
Ain't no team. It's a pit stop for me, baby.
团队个屁,我不会待久
I'm on the verge of leaving all y'all suckers behind.
我很快就要甩掉你们
Actually, you're on the verge of being suspended.
你很快就要被停职
Have a nice day.
糗大了吧
Somebody said I was getting suspended?
我要被停职?
Quit playing, girl.
别闹了
I know you playing.
我知道你在耍我
Johnson, somebody told you I was getting suspended?
有人说我被停职吗?
This is a problem.
事情很棘手
All I need is a foreign national getting his head blown off...
我不想让外国人被打死
and turning this into an international incident.
变成外交事件
What can we do? He's on his way.
他正赶来,怎么办?
Call the field office. Have them send over a rookie.
请总部派一名菜鸟干员
We'll have him escort this guy around town for a couple of days
我们陪同这家伙去闲逛一两天
pretend to follow leads, show him some sights,
假装带他到处看看风景
keep him out of our way.
然后把他送走
Warren, you sure you want to do that to one of our own men?
真要派联邦干员吗?
What do you suggest?
你说呢?
As long as we're going to humiliate someone...
既然这是个烂差事
might as well be LAPD.
就找洛城警探吧
Even if I had an extra man,
即使我有人手
who would want such a bullshit assignment?
也不肯干这烂差事
Well, it's a disgrace to me.
简直就是丢脸
It's a disgrace to my department. It's a disgrace to...
丢我们警局的脸...
Dan, I'm sending someone right over.
丹,我马上派人去
Cap... I know you read the paper.
队长,你一定看过报
They lying. You know I wouldn't do nothing like that.
不是真的,我不会乱来
They over-exaggerate. You know how the paper is.
报纸都是夸大其词 你也知道内幕的
They just want a story.
讲故事罢了
Two officers were shot.
两名警察被射伤
One man lost a pinkie.
一名员警的小指被射断
But didn't nobody die.
又没有死人
You destroyed half a city block.
你炸掉半条街
That block was already messed up.
那条街早该拆了
And you lost a lot of evidence.
物证全都被毁
Still got a little bit left.
还有一点点
What you did was dangerous and completely against policy.
你擅自行动、危害民众
And not only that.
我想说的是
You did a good job.
你表现得很好
What?
什么?
Everyone around here is image-conscious.
大家都小心得过头
Everybody's afraid of their own shadow.
老是怕出什么错
It's nice to meet an L.A. Detective who's willing to lay it on the line
你为了抓坏人奋不顾身
Captain, that's the way I feel.
我也是这么想
That's what I've been trying to tell everybody.
我一直在跟大家说
Every so often we have to let the public know
有时候得让市民知道
we can still blow shit up.
我们还是能搞爆炸
You goddamn right! That's the only way I work, Cap.
说得好,这是我的作风
So I ain't getting suspended?
我没被停职吗?
Suspended? Are you kidding?
停职?怎么会?
I don't even know why I said that.
当我没说过
I just got a call from the FBI.
调查局来找我
A 10-year-old daughter of a Chinese diplomat was kidnapped.
中共领事的女儿被绑架
And they want you on the case.
他们要你负责
FBI wnat me?
FBI要我?
That's right.
没错
Stop lying. I don't lie.
别唬我 没有
Tell the truth. I'm telling the truth.
老实说吧 我说的是实话
Thank you, Captain.
谢谢你,队长
Congratulations, Carter.
恭喜了,卡特
Appreciate it! You are going to the show.
多谢了 你升官了
I'm going to look out for you when I go to the top.
等我平步青云后就处理你的事情
I'll make you mayor.
让你当市长
I'd rather you didn't.
不用了
Listen up! If anybody need me...
听好了,谁想找我
I'm going to be working a big, big case for the FBI!
我要替FBI办一件大案子
Take care of that for me.
好好替我停车
I need one of those earpieces immediately, all right?
马上给我准备耳机
How you doing?
你好
Cross check the personned records with the new list from Interpol.
核对国际刑警送来的名单
See if you can make any matches or connections.
试着找出什么关联
Okay, boys, what do we got?
好了,有什么线索?
Have we checked the Consul personal records?
领事馆的人事记录呢?
I want to know who's he been talking with,
我想知道他都跟谁交谈过
who's he been dealing with.
跟什么人有来往
Okay, give me the story. Any demands?
向我报告,绑匪有何要求?
Any fingerprints? Have we interviewed his staff?
采到指纹...问过证人吗?
Whitney, who is this?
老魏,这家伙是谁?
Give me a copy of that.
给我一份副本
James Carter, FBI.
詹姆斯卡特,FBI
Warren, he's here for the special assignment.
他是特别任务的人选
I'm Agent-in Charge Warren Russ.
我是负责人罗华伦
It's good to have you on board.
很高兴有你加入
I been waiting for this.
我一直在等待
You guys take a while to process an application.
需要一段时间获得批准
Well, Carter...
卡特
your particular assignment is considered G-14 classified.
这是G14级最高机密任务
Why don't you and I take a walk and I'll fill you in.
我跟你出去边走边说
Okay, Warren.
好吧,华伦
G-14 classified.
G14级最高机密
That's good.
他真会掰
You don't understand, this is my dream.
你不理解的,这是我的梦想
I'm excited about working with the FBI.
当FBI干员就是我的梦想
I'm glad. Listen.
那敢情好,听好了
His name is Lee, and the director considers this a top priority.
他姓李,局长亲自交待的
No disrespect, sir, but he'll get in my way.
恕我直言,他会妨碍我
I'm not used to having a partner.
我不习惯有搭档
If I'm going to handle the situation for you, I must work alone.
我办案通常都是单枪匹马
Cartel... he is the situation.
他就是你的案子
Must be a misunderstanding.
你一定搞错了
I'm here for the kidnapping. The liggle girl?
我是来办小女孩绑票案的
Forget the firl. Your assignment is Lee.
别管她,你负责姓李的
Who is Lee and what kind of assignment is that?
这算哪门子的案子?
Lee is a foreign detective. A friend of the consul's.
李探长是韩领事的朋友
You're to keep him out of sight and away from danger. Understand?
你要保护他不受伤,懂吗?
I understand. You want me to babysit, but I don't do that.
你要我当保姆,我不干
I came for the big assignment.
我是来办大案子的
Truth is, this is an FBI operation...
老实说,FBI的案子
and I don't need help from the LAPD or some Chung King cop.
不用洛城或香港来的警察插手
You got it?
懂不懂?
Why didn't you put one of your men on this top-priority case?
你干嘛不找自己的手下?
What I supposed to do with him?
我要跟他做什么?
I don't give a damn.
我不管
I don't want to see him or you until this is resolved.
反正我不想再见到你们
His plane arrives in an hour.
班机一小时后到
We want to make a good impression, Carter.
好好接待他
It's his first trip to America.
他第一次来美国
This is bullshit!
太欺负人了
Tell me you speak English.
你会讲英语吧
I'm Detective Carter. Do you speak any English?
我是卡特警探,你会英文吗?
Do you understand the words that are coming out of my mouth?
你听得懂我说的话吗?
I cannot believe this shit.
我真是衰到家了
First I get a bullshit assignment.
先是接到这烂差事
Now. Mr. Rice-A-Roni...
这个功夫小子
...don't even speak American.
又不会说英文
Come on, man. My ride over here.
来吧,那是我的车
Put yoru bag in the back.
行李放后座
Put your bag in the back!
把行李放在后车座上
No...
不,不,不
You put your own shit in the back! I'm not a skycap.
你自己动手,我不是小弟
I'm FBI. You understand?
我是联邦干员,懂吗?
What the hell you think this is?
拜托你搞清楚状况
Captain, I don't think this is funny.
队长,这不好笑
Captain. You need to call the FBI and tell them you made a mistake.
打给FBI说你弄错了
I can't do that, Carter.
办不到,卡特
I'm sure that you and Mr. Lee will have a nice time together.
你和李先生一定会玩得开心
I'm warning you. Call the FBI
我警告你,通知FBI
or I'll drop his ass off at Panda Express.
否则我在熊猫快餐馆放他鸽子
Drop this case, Carter,
停下这个案子 卡特
you're suspended for two months without pay.
你将被停职二个月,而且没有工钱
All right, you can forget about being mayor, then.
好吧,那你也当不上市长
Congratulations, Carter,
恭喜你 卡特
it looks like you finally got yourself a partner.
你终于找到搭档了
One little pinkie get blowed off, man, everybody tripping.
断了根小指就拿我开刀
"Chinese Consul"?
中共领事馆?
That's one place you can't go.
你不能去那儿
I ain't getting fired for nobody. You going to pay my bills?
要是我失业你养我吗?
Soo Yung.
素洋
That's the little girl?
那个小女孩?
Say something.
说话呀
They all think it's real funny.
他们都在笑我
Give Carter the big G-14 classified case.
什么狗屁G14级机密任务
I'll show the FBI they don't know who they playing with.
这下FBI把我惹毛了
I'll solve this case myself.
我要自己办案
That's right.
看我的吧
I want to show you something first. Look familiar?
我带你看样东西,眼熟吧?
Just like home, ain't it? Look. Just like home.
像不像你的家乡呀?
I ain't never been to China, but I bet it probably look like this.
我没去过中国,大概就是这样
Star maps!
明星地图
Look, look. John Wayne.
你看,约翰韦恩
John Wayne? You know John Wayne?
你知道约翰韦恩?
John Wayne.
约翰韦恩
Yeah, hang out with the Duke.
留下来陪老公爵
I'll be back. You may see one of your cousins around here.
我马上回来,跟你老表聊聊
Find them and stalk them! Star maps!
挖出明星的八卦
Right here! Star maps, people!
明星地图,这儿有在卖
You got the address to Michael Jackson house?
你有麦可杰克森的地址吗?
Never-Neverland?
梦幻岛?
You can't come around my job! That's harassment.
别来骚扰我,好吗?
Checking on you.
我来看你乖不乖
I'm legit, selling star maps. It's all I sell.
这是正当生意,我只卖地图
Legit, my ass.
正当个屁
What you and your Asian gang friends talk about? Kidnapping?
你和亚裔帮派聊到绑票案吗?
I don't know nothing.
我什么也不知道
Give me a star map...
我要买地图
for $45. Do you understand?
45块一张,说不说?
I don't know about a kidnapping.
我不知道绑票案
But some dude's buying guns, explosives
不过有人买了一大堆枪和炸药
and people like he's starting a war.
人们以为他要开战呢
What's his name? I don't know.
他叫什么? 我不知道
You don't know his name?
你不知道他叫什么?
For $45, I don't know.
只给45块我不知道
For $45, you tell me something.
你得说些线索
I don't know nothing for $45.
我什么也不知道
I didn't tell you nothing!
我什么也没说
Lee!
李
Didn't I tell you to wait for me?
我叫你等我
What the hell you doing on this bus?
你上巴士干什么?
You think I'm playing with you?
我不是说着玩的
Think I'm playing? I ain't playing with you. Sit down.
我不想跟你玩游戏,坐下来
It's okay. It's all right. FBI.
没事,联邦干员
Take a picture. Wait a minute.
尽管拍,等一下
All right.
够了
Out of my way! Watch out!
让开,小心
FBI. Stop this bus.
FBI,快停车
Stop!
停车
FBI. I need this motorcycle. Get off!
我要这辆摩托车,下车
Get out of the car. Get out of the car now!
给我下车,马上下车
Where are you going? Didn't I tell you to stay by the Duke?
我叫你别乱跑,你想去哪里?
What are you doing?
你搞什么鬼?
Mind your own business, stay in the car.
别多管闲事
I just wanted to find out where you was going.
我想知道你去哪里
I don't want to shoot you. I wanted to go with you.
我要跟你去
What's happening here?
这是怎么回事?
Put the gun down. Put the gun down! I ain't playing with you!
把枪放下,我不是闹着玩
Think I'm playing?
想死吗?
Don't move!
别动
Drop your guns.
把枪放下
Hey, man... look. FBI.
老兄,我是FBI
I'm policeman.
我是警察
I'm just showing him how to take a gun from a suspect.
我正在教他怎么夺枪
All of a sudden you speaking English.
你怎么突然会讲英文?
A little. "A little," my ass. You lied to me.
只会一点点 才怪,你骗我
I didn't say I didn't. You assumed I didn't.
我没骗你,是你假设的
"Assume" I kick your Beijing ass. I ain't scared of you.
小心我扁你,我才不怕你
I know you know that tricky shit.
虽然你会功夫
I'm not responsible for your assumption.
你自己笨,别怪我
You full of shit. You understand? You full of shit.
这是什么屁话?
Not being able to speak is not the same as not speaking.
不说话不等于是哑巴
You seem as if you like to talk.
你这么爱说话
I let people talk who like to talk.
我就让你说个够
It makes it easier to find out how full of shit they are.
反正你说的都是屁话
What the hell did you just say?
你刚才说什么?
I like people to talk because it's easy...
你说的都是屁话
So I'm the one full of shit?
我说的是屁话?
We both full of shit.
我们都一样
You full of shit.
你这个骗子
I'm going to kick your ass.
我要揍扁你
Don't nobody do that but me.
这一招我也会
You want me to kick your ass, don't you?
你真是欠扁,是吧?
You must take me to see Consul Han right away.
带我去找韩领事
Just sit there and shut up. This ain't no democracy.
给我闭嘴,这不是民主国家
Yes, it is.
这里是
No, it ain't. This is the United States of James Carter now.
才不是,这是我的国家
I'm the president. I'm the emperor. I'm the king.
我是总统、国王、皇帝
I'm Michael Jackson, you Tito.
我是麦可杰克森,你谁都不是
Your ass belong to me.
你得听我的
Why would they not want my help?
他们为什么不要我帮忙?
They don't give a damn about you.
他们懒得理你
They don't like you. I don't like you.
我和他们都不喜欢你
I don't care. I'm here for the girl.
我是来救小女孩的
She don't like you.
她也不喜欢你
Nobody likes you.
没人喜欢你
You came all the way here for nothing.
你白来了
You ain't going to be...
你别想要...
Beach Boys.
海滩男孩合唱团
Hell, no. You didn't just touch my radio?
想都别想,别碰我的收音机
They are great American music.
最好的美国音乐
The Beach Boys will get you an ass-whupping.
小心我扁你
Don't ever touch a black man's radio, boy.
别碰老黑的收音机
You can do that in China, but you'll get your ass killed here
在中国没关系,在这儿会没命
I'm going to show you real music.
这是真正的美国音乐
That's music. You hear that?
这才够霹雳,听到吗?
Can you do that to The Beach Boys? Can you do that to The Beach Boys?
听海滩男孩能跳舞吗?
Hell, no.
才不能
I must get to the consulate. What are we doing here?
我要去领事馆,这是哪里?
It's called a shakedown. Serious police work.
我要抄这地方,重要警务
Whatch me handle my business and control the space.
看我怎么搞定他们
I want to help with the investigation. This is my case.
我要帮忙,这是我的案子
Your case?
你的案子?
You can back me up.
到一边凉快去吧
When we get in here, you follow my lead and do what I do. Okay?
待会我怎么做你就怎么做
What's up, my nigger? What's up?
怎么样,老黑? 怎么样?
Is this weed?
这是大麻吗?
Got a prescription?
有处方吗?
Where's it at? Where's it at?
在哪里?在哪里?
I should take you to jail.
我大可以抓你
For what?
凭什么?
That's a cigarette.
这只是香烟
This ciga-weed!
那是大麻烟
Look like a cigarette.
怎么看都是香烟
You better have glaucoma.
你有白内障
I do.
没错
What's up, my nigger?
怎么样,老黑?
Check that, baby.
瞧瞧是谁来了
What's happening, Carter?
你好吗,卡特?
Put the guns down. Put the guns down.
把枪放下,放下来
MC Hammer Daddy, put the goddamn gun down.
吹气老爹,把枪放下
I got questions and I need answers.
给我乖乖回答
Put them down.
把枪放下
Where the girl? What little girl?
那个小女孩呢? 什么小女孩?
The little girl. What little girl?
就是那个小女孩 什么小女孩?
The Chinese girl.
中国小女孩
I don't know about no girl!
我不知道什么小女孩
You know what I'm talking about!
你知道我在说什么!
I'll take you in if I don't get answers.
得不到答案,我抓你坐牢
Carter, put the gun down.
卡特,把枪放下
Don't act like you know me. You don't.
装作你不认识我
I see what's going on. Y'all trying to play me like a fool
我知道了,你们想要骗我
Lee, go outside. It'll get dangerous in here.
李,出去,这里太危险
I may have questions.
我也有问题要问
Wait by the bar. Remember what I told you?
听好,到吧台等我
Back me up. I'm going to take care of everything.
帮帮忙,我能搞定
You sure? I'm sure. Now go on. Go on.
真的吗? 当然了,去吧,快去
Think I'm playing.
我不是开玩笑
Hurry up!
快去
Come here.
给我过来
Don't come in my business scaring me. Goddamn.
该死,别跑来吓我
I was just playing. Give me a hug.
我只是装的,抱一下
I'm showing that rookie the ropes.
我是吓吓那菜鸟
Why didn't you come to church Sunday?
你都不上教堂
I had some things to take care of. But I made the night service.
我很忙,不过我晚上有去
Come here. I want to holler at you.
过来,我要问你
What's up?
问什么?
Who's running around town buying explosives and weapons?
谁在到处买枪和炸药?
I don't know nothing about that.
我不知道
Luke, I know what you do.
路克,我知道你卖军火
The only reason I ain't busted you because you my cousin...
你是我表弟,要是我抓你
and it'd kill Aunt Bootsie.
布阿姨会难过死了
Why put Aunt Bootsie in this?
你提她干嘛?
I ain't playing.
我不是说着玩
She got a bad heart, but if I have to, I'll bust your ass.
就算她心脏不好我照样抓你
Tell me something.
给我一点线索
The word in Chinatown is there's a new dude in town
听说唐人街来了个狠角色
bad-ass dude out of Hong Kong, buying up every goddamn thing.
香港人,他在到处搜购武器
What's his name?
他叫什么?
I don't know. He ain't buying from me.
不知道,我没卖给他
You don't know his name?
你不知道他叫什么?
Nobody know his name.
没有人知道
What's up, my nigger?
怎么样,老黑?
What did you just say?
你说什么?
What's up, my nigger?
怎么样,老黑?
Come here.
过来
What you say, boy?
你说什么,小子?
I don't want trouble.
我不想惹麻烦
Please... I said I don't want trouble.
求求你们,我不想惹麻烦
That's bad for you.
吸烟对身体不好
Where the little girl at? What little girl?
小女孩在哪里? 什么小女孩?
You know what firl I'm talking about!
你清楚得很
You better take your hands off my suit.
把你的臭手拿开
Your mama bought me this suit. It's my favorite suit.
衣服是你老妈买给我的
Now let me go.
给我放手
I'll see you Thanksgiving. Appreciate it.
感恩节见,多谢了
Get your big Happy Meal ass over in the corner.
给我滚到角落去
I'm still the law here!
我才是老大
Next time I come in, y'all better clean this shit up!
下次最好给我乖一点
And brush your teeth! Let's go.
记得要刷牙,走吧
What are we doing here?
来这里干嘛?
I'm getting something to eat.
买东西吃
You want anything? A Cup of Noodles or something?
你要什么?泡面?
Carter, stop wasting my time. I made a promise to Soo Yung.
别浪费时间,我答应过素洋
You right. I have been wasting your time. I'm sorry.
真抱歉,我浪费了你的时间
Let me get something to eat. Then I'll take you where you want.
等我先吃饱再带你去
Okay?
可以吗?
Okay.
好吧
Shake?
一言为定
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
YOu not the only one with quick hands.
我的身手也不赖
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
Shit.
可恶
I got you a beef and bean burrito.
我替你买了墨西哥牛肉卷
We have a taxicab approaching. The man stepping out. Asian.
有辆计程车,亚裔男子下车
About 5-10.
五尺十寸
Someone's approaching the gate, dropped off by a cab.
有人坐计程车到领事馆
Tell them to intercept.
把他拦下来
Intercept.
拦下来
We will intercept.
我们去
Can I help you?
你有什么事?
I must see the Consul.
我要见领事
About what?
为什么?
Please, it's very important.
这件事很重要
Tell us why you need to see the Consul.
先说出你找领事有什么事
We'll tell you whether it's important.
我们再决定重不重要
Do you have identification?
你有身份证吗?
It's about his daughter.
是他女儿的事
Hands above your head!
手举起来
He asked about the Consul's daughter.
他提到领事的女儿
He asked about the daughter.
他提到那女孩
You don't understand. I was invited.
是他请我来的
Don't move! Throw your gun away.
别动,把枪丢掉
He's going to kill them.
他要杀死他们
Is everything all right?
没事吧?
You'll be safer on the second floor.
到二楼比较安全
I'm sorry. I'm sorry about this.
对不起,真是抱歉
He went over!
他翻过墙
He's on the grounds. Come on.
他进去了,快点
Stay away from the window, please.
别靠近窗口
Get down, now!
快趴下
Don't move!
别动
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉,我来晚了
Wait here.
你等一等
Mr. Russ, I think there has been a misunderstanding.
罗先生,这是个误会
It's all right. It's okay.
没事了
It's him... the guy from China.
是他,香港来的家伙
What?
什么?
Come in, please.
请进
Mr. Russ, I would like you to meet Detective Inspector Lee.
罗先生,这位是李探长
Excuse me very much.
真是抱歉
Oh, yes...
对了
your gun.
你的枪
Where the hell is Carter?
卡特在哪里?
I got to put up with this. Look at this.
我真是衰,你看看
You seen a little Asian dude about this height with a steering wheel on his arm?
你有没有看到一个这么高的小个子亚洲人
他的手里拿着方向盘?
Go screw yourself.
你去死吧
What did you say?
你说什么?
Go screw yourself.
去死吧
Take your sensitive ass up there and let me in. Out of the way!
快让我进去,滚开
Don't make me get out of this truck.
别逼我下车
When I get in here, I'm slapping somebody. I don't play that.
我一定要扁人,开什么玩笑
What happened? Your job was to keep...
怎么回事,你要负责...
It ain't my job to jump on buses.
我可不想跑来跑去
I do not do that! I am not Carl Lewis!
我不干,我又不是刘易士
Who is this man?
这个人是谁?
Sir, I can explain.
我可以解释
Agent Carter has been helping with my investigation.
卡特干员在协助我办案
He's upset that we have not done our job.
破不了案他很生气
Me and Lee are handling the situation.
我和李能处理
Everything's under control.
没有问题
We're on top of it. We'll get her back.
我们一定能找到她
He is passionate about finding your daughter.
他很努力找你女儿
Thank you.
谢谢你
We wanted Detective Lee to have one of our best men by his side.
我派最优秀的干员协助李探长
Agent Russ, this is a good time to tell the Consul the details of my assignment.
这是一个好机会,你应该跟领事说说我的任务
Yes.
是啊
Carter, can I speak to you for amoment?
卡特,我想跟你谈谈
You want to speak to me? In private?
你想私下跟我谈?
I see. This must be G-14 classified.
这一定是G14级最高机密
FBl-type stuff.
FBI的事
Let me call my captain, tell him what's going on.
我先打给队长,告诉他进展情况
We'll talk in a second.
等我一下
G-14. I love when the G-14 be coming around.
我最爱G14级最高机密了
Who is this? Hello?
你是谁?喂?
Am I speaking with FBI?
你是FBI干员吗?
The FBI? Yeah, this the FBI.
FBI?我是FBI干员
You are FBI?
你是FBI?
Yeah, this is the FBI.
对
If you want the girl back alive, listen and do not talk.
想要那女孩就乖乖听话
I'm listening. Let me get a pen.
我在听,我拿支笔
All right, cool.
好了
The drop will be made tonight, 11 p.m.
今晚十一点交钱
The amount will be 50 million dollar.
赎金是五千万元
Fifty million dollars?
五千万?
Who you think you kidnapped? Chelsea Clinton?
你以为你绑走柯林顿女儿吗?
Keep him talking.
继续说下去
In used currency. Nothing bigger than a 50.
我要旧钞,五十元以下
All right. Fifty million dollars, no problem.
好,五千万,没问题
I want 20 million in 50.
我要两千万的五十元钞票
Twenty million in 50s.
两千万要五十元钞票
Twenty million in 20s.
另外两千万要二十元钞票
两千万要二十元钞票
Ten million in 10.
一千万要十元钞票
And Ten million in 10s. You want any fives with that?
一千万十元,要五元钞票吗?
What is your name?
你叫什么名字?
What's yours? You called us. Why you want my name?
你呢?是你先打来的
I want to tell the Consul
我要告诉领事
who caused his daughter death because he talk too much.
他的话太多才会把女儿害死
All right, calm down.
好啦,冷静点
I'm trying to hook you up. I'm on yorr side.
我这是在帮你耶
You'll receive instruction for the drop half an hour before it is to be made.
交款前半小时我会再联络你
If it is successful, the firl will live.
我拿到赎金才放人质
I'll make sure you get the money. We can spend it together...
你一定拿得到,咱们一起花
because I don't even work for them.
反正我不是FBI的人
We got it. 620 South Broadway. Downtown.
查到了,南百老汇620号
Tactical Team One, proceed down Sixth to Sixth and Broadway.
一号小组,前往百老汇街
Team Two, I want you around the back at Fourth and Main.
二号小组,绕到缅因街后面
Set up a perimeter.
封锁现场
Take your team and cover the building floor by floor to the top. Move.
带上你的队伍,从上到下搜索那栋大楼,快去
They must not go into the building.
他们不能进去
Yeah, you right. Let's go tell them. Come on.
没错,快去跟他们说
Mr. Russ, you must pull your men back.
你要把人手叫回来
What the hell are you doing here? Where is Carter?
你在这儿干嘛?卡特呢?
Please listen to me!
请你听我说
Mr. Lee, you may be very competent...
虽然你很厉害
but the fact that you know this girl compromises your judgement.
但事实是你认识的这个女孩会影响你的判断力
Sir, if you were asking for $50 million,
他要求五千万元赎金
would you be in a place like that?
会躲在这种地方吗?
Get this clown away from me.
把这小丑带走
Take a hike.
快滚吧
Hey, man.
老兄
Why were you hiding?
你干嘛躲起来?
What're you talking about?
你在说什么?
You were hiding.
你躲起来
I bent down to tie my shoe and you was gone.
我只是蹲下去绑鞋带
Sir, the area is secured. Room's empty.
封锁现场,房间是空的
Damn it!
该死
Everybody, pull back!
大伙快撤退
Goddamn!
该死
Get some paramedics here, now!
快叫救护车
Evacuate the building. Get fire crews here.
进行撤退,快叫消防车
We got an explosion at Sixth and Broadway.
六街和百老汇街口发生爆炸
That ain't far enough, man!
我够不到,老兄
I ain't Kareem Abdul-Jabbar. Push it down some more.
我不是贾霸,下来一点
Don't come any... Stop.
不要过来,站住
Think I done broke my... Shit!
我好像扯断...该死
Who was that you was chasing?
你在追谁呀?
His name is Sang, from Hong Kong. Because of you, he got away.
香港来的桑,你害我把他追丢
Why you didn't tell me about the bridge?
你怎么没警告我?
I did. No, you did not.
我有 才没有
我有 没有
I said, "Stop!"
我叫你站住
I don't understand what you be saying!
我没有听懂
What?
什么?
You see what I'm saying?
这就对了
What's this in your hand?
你拿的是什么?
He dropped it.
他掉下来的
Oh, shit. Come on.
可恶,走吧
Where we going?
上哪儿?
I messed up my suit.
我把西装弄皱了
Fifteen seconds.
十五秒
Make a decision.
赶快决定
Johnson!
强森
Shit!
该死
Did I come at a bad time?
我来得不是时候?
I got bad news for you, Johnson. We're all dead.
坏消息,我们都死了
I was distracted, sir.
我受到干扰
Distractions occur in the field. That's why we call this practice.
一定会有干扰,所以才要演习
If you can't handle the pressure, then quit.
你受不了压力就退出
Yes, sir.
是,长官
Give her a break.
别找她的碴
Don't worry about him. How you doing? What's going on?
别管他,你好吗?
Give me some love.
亲一下吧
Why are you tormenting me?
你怎么老是折磨我?
Is that any way to treat a friend? I came to see how you're doing?
别这样嘛,我来看你耶
And I need some help.
我也要你帮个忙
Help?
帮忙
I know you have feelings for me...
我知道你对我有意思
but we got to put that aside. There's a girl's life at stake.
不过先别提,那女孩有危险
Since when do you care about anybody but yourself?
你怎么关心起别人?
Please, take a look at this.
你看看
We found this on the kidnapper. Tell me what it is.
绑匪掉的,这是什么?
Now you want me to work with you?
你要我跟你搭档?
I don't have time for this. I got my own shit to deal with.
不要这样,我的麻烦够多了
Who are you?
你是谁?
Sorry we got you in trouble.
抱歉我们害你惹上麻烦
He's sorry he got you in trouble. Tell me something about this.
是他害你惹麻烦,别怪我
It's a remote. Could be nitro cap, cross delay.
这是摇控器,用来引爆炸弹
Not homemade. Definitely not American.
肯定不是美国制造
It could open a garage door or blow up some C-4.
可以开车库或引爆塑胶炸弹
C-4?
塑胶炸弹?
Yeah, C-4.
对,塑胶炸弹
This means so much to me.
谢谢你的帮忙
Go, go, go.
快滚吧
Sorry about spreading those rumors on Christmas about us sleeping together.
我不该散播谣言说咱们在圣诞节上过床
What?
什么?
He's just joking.
他在开玩笑
Bobby, what's up, man?
巴比,你好吗?
I need to see Clive Cobb.
我要见克莱夫
No way, Carter. It's lights out. They locked down.
不行,现在不准见人犯
Want me to lose my job?
别害我被炒鱿鱼
I got you this job. You better open the gate and let me in.
是我帮你找到差事的,快开门
Can't do it.
不行
Didn't I turn my back when you bought that weed?
大麻那档事我饶过你
I was splitting it with you!
那次你也有份
Didn't I give you the bigger half? Bobby, do me this favor.
你分的最多,帮个忙嘛
Shit. You got five minutes.
好吧,五分钟
Hey, Cobb, your two brothers are here to see you!
龙兄虎弟来找你了
Clive, how you doing, man?
克莱夫,你好吗?
You got balls coming here.
你还敢跑来?
I was around. I figured you'd be bored.
我正好经过,你一定很无聊
I came to see how you was doing.
所以顺便来看看你
What do you want?
你要什么?
I came to bring you a gift.
我来送你礼物
You got time on your hands and I brought you a toy.
反正你有空,我带了玩具来
I don't want that. You don't?
我不要 是吗?
I heard you like to play with stuff like this.
听说你爱玩这调调
I don't play with stuff like that. I don't know what it is.
我才不爱玩,这是什么?
Never sold this to nobody?
你没卖给别人?
How could I? I don't know what it is.
我都不知道这是什么
Maybe if you hold it. Want to hold it?
摸摸看,要不要?
I don't want to touch it.
我不想摸
Why you don't want to touch it? 'Cause I don't want to touch it.
为什么 是我不想
Scared of it? You think I'm stupid?
你怕吗?我才没有那么笨
Stupid enough to get busted.
你够笨才被抓
You want my fingerprints on it to frame me.
你想骗我留下指纹
Why would I do that? You think I'll trick you again?
怎么会?我不会骗你
I don't have to.
我没有必要
You'll do life when they find out you killed the girl.
反正等他们发现你杀死那女孩,你就得坐一辈子牢
I don't know anything.
我什么也不知道
Ain't what I heard. That's what I'll tell everybody.
我听说你什么都知道
I don't care what you heard.
我不在乎
I got a big mouth.
我是大嘴巴
Let me tell you something.
你给我听好
I don't know anything about it, so kiss my fat ass.
我就是不知道,怎么样?
It'd take me all day to kiss your fat ass.
你这浑蛋真是欠扁
What'll you do? Want some of this? I'll give you all you want.
干嘛?想打架?尽管来吧
Give me a name.
说出一个名字
I ain't telling you shit.
我什么也不说
She's only 11 years old.
她才十一岁
I don't want her to die.
我不能让她死
Look at the picture.
看看这照片
I don't care about him or you! I care about the girl!
我不在乎你们,我只在乎她
Give me the name.
快招出来
The guy's name is Juntao.
那家伙叫钟涛
I never seen him.
我没见过他
Where can I find him?
他在哪里?
Foo Chow Restaurant, Chinatown.
唐人街福州餐馆
Do yourself a favor. Get rid of this guy. He'll get you killed.
你最好甩掉他,他会害死你
I'll come and bring your fat ass some cookies. We appreciate this.
下次我带饼干给你,谢了
That's it.
在这儿
What are we waiting for?
我们还等什么?
We scoping the place out.
我们得先探探路
We ain't going to run in. That's how you get shot.
硬闯进去一定会受伤
I'm falling asleep.
我快要睡着了
What is it good for? Absolutely nothing.
有什么用?一点也没用
Man, you don't know nothing about no "War".
你不会唱《战争》这首歌
Everybody knows "War."
每个人都会唱
What is it good for? Absolutely nothing.
有什么用?一点也没用
Good God, you all.
上天保佑
It ain't "you all". It's "y'all".
是老天保佑啦
You sound like a karate movie. Y'all.
你好像在吆喝卖药
Say it from here with some soul. Y'all.
你要有点感情
Let me show your goofy ass how to do this.
我就教你几招吧
Come on, come on.
来呀,来呀
Do that again. Do it again.
再来一次,再来一次
Like this?
这样吗?
One will be inserted in the suitcase. The other will be on you.
一个装在皮箱,一个在你身上
When you make the drop.
你交钱的时候...
Do we have it?
好了吗?
Pick it up.
接吧
You have what the else about.
有没有拿到钱?
I do.
有
I hope now you realize how serious I am.
希望你知道我是玩真的
Take the money to the alley
把钱带到巷子
behind the FOO CHOW Restaurant in Chinatown
就在中国城福州餐馆的后面
You have twenty-nine minutes left.
你只有29分钟
Go alone.
你自己去
Damn, Chin, this some greasy shit.
真是的,这道菜太油腻
Ain't you got no better food,
没有清淡一点的
like chicken wings, ribs, fries or something?
像是烤排骨、炸薯条之类的
Chinese food. No sould food here.
只有中国菜,没有老黑菜
Ididn't say soul food. I said, "better food."
我没说老黑,我是说清淡
I don't want that greasy shit. How do you sell a box of grease?
我不爱油腻,这太油了
Umchilia what?
什么玩意?
Hey, come on.
过来
I'm no punk bitch!
我不是你马子
I ain't no punk bitch neither!
我也不是你马子
I'm no punk bitch.
我不是你马子
I'll knock your hat off.
小心我扁你
Man, what you got me eating?
你点了什么?
That's eel.
鳗鱼
Is it good?
好吃吗?
Very good.
很好吃
What you got?
你在吃什么?
Camel's hump.
驼峰
What?
什么?
Camel's hump.
驼峰
Kind of good!
挺好吃的
Need a little hot sauce, but it's kind of good.
沾点辣椒酱会更好吃
We're still waiting?
还在等吗?
How do we get this guy, Juntao? How we know he exists?
该怎么逮到钟涛这家伙?
Nobody ever seen him.
没有人见过他
I know. He killed my partner.
我知道,他杀死我的搭档
I'm sorry about that, man.
很遗憾,老兄
That's why I don't have a partner. I learned that from my daddy.
所以我像我爸不找搭档
Your daddy was apoliceman?
你爸是警察?
Fifteen years, LAPD.
洛城警局,十五年
My father was also a policeman.
我父亲也是警察
He was a cop?
是吗?
Not a cop. An officer, a legend all over Hong Kong.
他是警官,香港传奇人物
My daddy a legend all over America.
我老爸是美国传奇人物
My daddy once arrest 15 people in one night by himself.
一个晚上就逮了十五个人
My daddy arrest 25 by himself.
我父亲逮了二十五个
My daddy saved 5 crackheads from a burning building by himself.
我老爸从火堆救出五个人
My daddy once caught a bullet with his bare hands.
我父亲徒手接住子弹
Ny daddy would kick you daddy's ass from here to China or Japan,
我老爸能把你老爸踢到爪哇国
wherever you from and up that Great Wall.
然后再踢到万里长城
Don't talk about my father.
别批评我父亲
Don't talk about my daddy.
别说我老爸坏话
That your boy?
就是他吗?
Yes. Let's go.
对,走吧
I better go in first. Nobody going to recognize me.
我先进去,没人认得我
I'll wait five minutes.
我等五分钟
Hey, take my ID. If anything go wrong...
拿我的警徽,要是出事
you bust in like you LAPD.
假装是洛城警探闯进来
This won't work. I'm not 6'1".
不行,我不够高
Yes, it will. It's all about attitude, all right?
当然行,只要有架势
Flip it open. Flip it closed. Do it fast.
只要亮一下就行,动作要快
You'll get it. Look.
你学得会的
Take this.
拿去
Hey, man, act like you from out of town.
装一副外地人的样子
I am from out of town.
我本来就是外地人
Don't act like a cop.
别显得像个警察
Act like a tourist or something. Don't be obvious.
装成观光客,不要太嚣张
Okay. No problem.
好,没问题
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Hey, how you doing?
你好
For one?
一位吗?
No, for two. I'm here to meet with Mr. Juntao.
两位,我来找钟涛
I'm sorry, I don't know Mr. Juntao.
抱歉,我不认识他
You don't understand. I'm his lawyer, legal advisor.
我是他的律师
He got into some shit, said to come here.
他有麻烦,叫我来找他
I'm very busy. I ain't got time to come, but I'm here.
我很忙,不过还是来了
My wife wants me home, my baby shit all over, needs diapers.
我老婆要我回家替宝宝换尿布
Get Mr. Juntao?
快去叫他
I already told you, I don't know him.
我说我不认识他
Think I came here for nothing?
我不想白跑一趟
Want to give me gas money? Got $5 on you?
给我点油钱,五块钱
Go upstairs and tell Mr. Juntao get down here.
到楼上叫他下来
Thank you.
谢谢你
Can I sit right here?
我能坐吗?
Right here?
这儿吗?
Y'all got any eel?
有鳗鱼吗?
Sure.
有
How's your camel hump?
驼峰好吃吗?
Excuse me.
对不起
Where is Roscoe's Chicken and Waffles?
南方炸鸡店在哪里?
This way?
这儿吗?
Sorry, I'm from out of town.
抱歉,我是外地人
Thank you.
谢谢你
What's that?
那是什么?
Excuse me.
对不起
Somebody's asking for Juntao.
老板,有人在下面找钟涛
有人在下面找钟涛
Bring him up?
把他带上来吗?
Bring him up.
带他上来
No, wait.
等等
Get the girl out of here.
把人质带走
Make sure those two don't leave.
别让那两个人活着离开
Are you ready to order?
先生你决定了没有?
No.
没有
Fine.
好
Juntao will see you.
钟涛要见你了
It's about time.
该是时候了
Stop it! Let me go!
住手,放开我
This is tight.
棒呆了
This ain't nothing like downstairs. Y'all got it going.
比楼下好多了,正点
What's up, man?
怎么样?
What y'all watching?
看什么看?
Where Juntao at?
钟涛的人呢?
Why y'all so quiet?
干嘛这么安静?
That was childish, man. That wasn't even called for!
太可恶了,你们真没礼貌
Now I came down here to see Juntao
我来找钟涛
because he told me to come down here
他自己叫我来的
because I'm his half-brother from Beijing.
我是他北京的兄弟
Me, him got the same mama. I'm Blackanese.
同母异父,我算是中黑人
We all the same. Wait a minute!
我们是同胞,住手
You going to kill me?
你要杀我?
Put the gun down, fight me like a man.
枪放下,咱们单打独斗
That's right, fight me like a man!
像个真正的男子汉
Anybody can shoot somebody.
三岁小孩都会用枪
That's what I'm talking about. Give me room.
这样才对,让开点
You don't know who you messing with I'll knock.
你们是找死
Which one of y'all kicked me?
是谁踢我?
Me.
我
All right.
好吧
Hold on. Let's talk about this.
你过来一下
Let's talk, hold it a minute.
好话好商量
What that mean?
你说什么?
It's a misunderstanding.
这是个误会
Let's pray about this.
祷告吧
FBI, huh?
联邦调查局?
No, I ain't FBI. I'm a security guard at the mall.
不是,我只是警卫
Now wipe yourself off.
擦一下
You're bleeding.
你在流血
He just playing, man. He playing, he didn't mean that.
他在开玩笑,不是说真的
He meant cut me loose.
他要替我松绑
Don't move.
别动
LAPD!
洛城警探
Watch out!
小心
Behind you!
你后面
Carter!
卡特
Freeze!
别动
We kicked y'all ass. All y'all! I got y'all ass.
我们把你们打得惨兮兮
Carter.
卡特
I'll kill you, man.
我要宰了你
Lee, over here!
李,那儿
Is that my gun?
是我的枪吗?
It is!
是耶
Let's go!
走吧
How you going to drop the badge?
你怎么会把警徽丢掉?
Then you threw the gun out the window...
你还把枪丢出去
I got everything under control! Don't worry!
我都搞定了,别担心
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
我的老天
It's cool.
没事
Why am I not surprised to find you here.
又是你们两个
Dan, I want these two back at the consulate immediately.
把这两个家伙带回领事馆
Let's take a ride, gentlemen.
跟我走吧
You better get your hand off me. Hey man, he with me.
别碰我,他跟我一起的
Just let me explain. I'll start from the top.
让我从头跟你解释
We were making the drop.
我们在付赎金
Han was about to get his daughter back and you two screwed it up!
快要救出人质就被你们搞砸
Wait, didn't you hear what Leee siad?
你没听到李说的吗?
Mr. Lee is on his way to Hong Kong.
李先生正被送回香港
Get out before I file obstruction of justice charges against you.
快滚吧,别让我告你阻碍办案
We was about to solve this case...
我们快要破案了
You're no longer on this assignment, Carter!
你被撤下来了,卡特
Case closed.
别再说了
I only meant to help. Please forgive me.
我只是一心想帮忙,请原谅我
I must now rely on the FBI.
我只能依赖FBI把素洋找回来
They'll take you to the airport.
他们会送你到机场
Juntao was behind this.
我知道一定是钟涛干的
Juntao?
钟涛?
Consul Han!
韩领事
Sorry, sir.
对不起
It was all my fault.
全是我的错
Lee would never jeopardize your daughter's life. He loves her.
李很爱你女儿,不会害她
It's a little too late for apologies, sir.
现在道歉太迟了
Consul...
韩领事
we have a call...
绑匪来电
We're ready.
都好了
Pick it up!
接吧
The ransom is now 70 million.
现在赎金是七千万
I'll call tomorrow with instructions.
明天通知交钱方法
Deliver the money, or pick up the body of your daughter.
不交钱就收尸吧
You must understand, what happened tonight was not...
请你相信,今晚的事...
Daddy, are you okay?
爸爸你还好吧?
Soo Yung.
素洋
Tell them I will do whatever they...
跟他们说我一定照办
Soo Yung.
素洋
Sorry, man.
很遗憾,老兄
Be sorry for Soo Yung.
为素洋遗憾吧
(洛杉矶 国际机场)
No hot leads?
没有线索?
None.
没有
Listen, we're doing everything we can here, right?
听好,我们已经尽力而为
Tracing everything coming into the compound...
追查所有的电话
Excuse me, Consul. You have a guest.
对不起,你有访客
Jck, let me get back to you.
待会再打给你
Thomas.
汤玛斯
I'm sorry, my friend.
很遗憾,老友
I couldn't stand by and do nothing.
我不能坐视不顾
Hey, what's up, baby?
怎么样,宝贝?
May, you got guts calling me. I'm going to hang up.
你还敢找我,我要挂断了
Wait a minute, don't hang up.
等等,别挂断
You know what? You was right about me, all rigth?
我以前真是不应该
I'm sorry.
对不起
Are you on drugs?
你在嗑药吗?
You was right. I was egotistic, inconsiderate.
你说得没错,我自大无礼
I was self-centered. I ain't used to partners.
不顾别人死活
But it ain't about me, it's about the girl.
不过这次你要想想那小女孩
She'll die if we don't help her.
你不帮忙她就会死
You understand what I'm saying?
你懂吗?
Not yet, but keep talking.
还不懂,继续说
I think something's big going down tonight.
今晚会发生大事
I need to find out where the Consul will be.
告诉我领事在哪里
Think you can help me?
你能帮忙吗?
I'll see what I can do.
我会尽力而为
I don't need you to "see." I need you to do it. Can you do it?
别说你会尽力,我要你办到
Okay, Carter.
好吧,卡特
All right, one other thing.
很好,我再问你
What color panties you got on?
你的内裤什么颜色?
Consul Han, I want you to go to the Chinese Expo as you plan.
我要你照计划参加开幕晚会
Have the money in the control room. Be sure to make no more mistake.
把钱放在控制室,别乱来
I understand, but I want to speak with my daughter!
我要跟我女儿讲话
Excuse me, who's the captain on this plane?
对不起,机长是谁?
It don't matter.
算了
Tell the captain we got a problem on the left side of this plane.
跟他说飞机有点问题
The engine needs a new alternator.
引擎得换新的交流发电机
My supervisior say: "Go fix that plane.
我的老板说,“去修好飞机
Put that alternator on it.
安装那个发电机
Don't let that plane leave till I come."
先别让这班飞机起飞”
Tell the proper authorities not to move this plane...
千万别让人登机
before the FAA come and we in shit.
先等民航局检查过再说
Go on!
快去呀
What are you doing here?
你在这儿干嘛?
Get your ass up now.
起来吧
We got work to do.
咱们得干活
Go away. I've disgraced myself.
走开,我犯了错
What about the little girl?
小女孩呢?
Leave me alone. You could never understand.
别管我,你不会懂
A man like me?
你这什么意思?
You are devoted only to yourself.
你只管自己死活
You're ashamed of being an officer. You dishonor your father's name.
丢了警局也丢了你父亲的脸
You know nothing about my father.
你不认识我老爸
You say he's a legend.
你说他是传奇人物
My father was a legend
我爸的确是
killed making a routine traffic stop...
他在开罚单的时候遇害
by some punk who didn't want no ticket.
有个混混对他不爽
His partner's supposed to back him up, but never did.
他的搭档却没有出来帮他
My father was as devoted as you.
我老爸跟你一样尽职
And now he's dead. And for what?
他为什么殉职?
A traffic ticket and some punk? What's the honor in that?
为了张罚单?这有何尊严?
You believe your father wasted his life, died for nothing?
你认为他死得没有意义?
Then prove me wrong.
请你证明我错了
For 15 years, until China resumed control of Hong Kong
香港回归前十五年来
Juntao was the most powerful crime lord in southeast Asia.
钟涛是势力最大的黑道老大
The British tried to close down his operation.
英国政府想打垮他
But we failed.
却失败了
But why the Consul's daughter?
他为何绑走领事的女儿?
Detective Inspector Lee helped me
李探长帮助我
raid every known asset of Juntao's operation.
把他们一网打尽
We confiscated millions in weapons, cash
没收价值数千万的枪支、现金
and a collection of Chinese art that was unsurpassed in the world.
和价值连城的古董
Then Juntao disappeared. No witnesses.
后来他消失无踪,没人看过他
Do you really think he'll kill the girl?
你认为他会撕票?
My advice is...
我建议你
pay the money.
付出赎金
Consul? I'm going upstairs to make the drop.
领事,我要上楼交钱
I want you to remain calm, as if nothing's wrong.
请你装作没有事
Don't leave Agent Whitney's side even for a moment.
不要离开魏干员一步
I understand.
我知道
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. I am Consul Han.
各位晚安,我是韩领事
On behalf of the People's Republic of China,
代表中华人民共和国
thank you for coming.
欢迎各位到来
I am pleased to present 5000 years of China's history and heritage.
我有幸介绍中国五千年的宝藏
A collection witch, until recently, was thought to be lost forever.
这些古物最近才被发现
This some nice shit.
好棒的古董
Buddha'd go good in my bathroom.
佛像适合摆我家
Hey, this is the history of my country.
这是中国的历史文物
Priceless pieces of Chinese culture.
象征中国文化的无价之宝
If anything gets damaged...
要是有所损坏
Don't worry. Ain't nothing going to happen to this.
别怕,不会有事的
And now, we can pass them on...
现在,我们终于能够...
...to our children.
...传承给下一代
Pardon me.
对不起
I seen that guy at that Chinese restaurant.
我在餐馆看过这家伙
Consul Han has been fighting flu for the past few days,
韩领事这几天感冒
so perhaps I should finish what he started.
让我替他说完
First we got to clear out the riffraff.
先把这些人赶走
Anybody stay behing, they got something to lose.
留下来的就是坏蛋
Wait here. I'll be back.
我马上回来
...in creating a peaceful future between our two countries.
...为了中美两国的未来
The more we see differences and similarities...
只有互相交流和了解...
Excuse me.
对不起
I'm Detective Carter from the LAPD.
我是洛城警探卡特
We got Carter down here.
卡特在那儿
What is going on?
怎么回事?
We received a threat on the building.
我们收到炸弹威胁
We ask if you exit the building as soon as possible
请各位尽速离开
and please do not panic.
请不要惊慌
Did you hear what I said? Get out the door!
听到吗?快逃命吧
There's a bomb here.
这里有炸弹
What's this panic about? Have the agents hold positions.
搞什么?大家守住岗位
Everybody, take cover, hold your positions.
大伙儿守住岗位
Get your ass out the building.
滚出大楼
Lady, put the glass down, get out of here.
拜托,放下酒杯,快逃吧
Woman, the exit over there or you'll get your head blowed off.
出口在那儿,你不要命吗?
Come on, come on!
快呀,快呀
Come on, titty, titty! Get them titties out of here!
快逃命吧,快点
Somebody grab Carter!
抓住卡特
Juntao.
钟涛
你就是钟涛
Consul Han, six blocks of C-4 are wired to your daughter outside.
你女儿身上绑了六块塑胶炸弹
Before the changeover, most of this exhibition
香港回归前这些古物
was in the hands of a single private collector.
属于一名私人收藏家所有
Me.
就是我
I worked most of my life
我辛苦一辈子
to acquire and catalog these priceless pieces you see before you
才收集到你们眼前的无价之宝
And then in one fell swoop...
没想到一下子...
it was taken from me.
...就被夺走
But tonight
不过今晚...
I shall be paid in full.
...我会得到补偿
Don't move!
别动
She dies if I press this button.
我按下去她就死
Just be patient.
有点耐心
My transportation will be here shortly.
马上就有人来接我
Stay calm.
冷静点
I was going to tell you, you're in the red zone.
你的车停在红线
There's cops all over.
到处都是警察
Didn't know I could do that, did you? Put your hands up!
没想到吧?手举起来
I ain't going to kill you. I'm just going to kick your ass!
我不会杀你,我会扁你
Tell your friends about me.
多替我宣传吧
How you doing?
你没事吗?
We been looking for you. I'm Carter from the LAPD.
我是洛城警探卡特
Everything's okay now. I'll take you to your daddy, all right?
不会有事的,我带你找爸爸
First thing I'll do, I'll take this vest off.
不过我先帮你脱掉背心
Don't touch it!
不能碰
I think it'll be safer if we take it off.
脱下来比较安全
I heard them say it will explode.
他们说脱下来就会爆炸
Okay, I think it'd be safer if we leave it on. Don't move.
那就不要脱,别动
Where are you?
你在哪里?
I'll be there about five minutes.
大概还有五分钟就可以到了
Everything is fine.
现在一切都很顺利
Over!
完毕
Don't move!
别动
Hold your positions!
不要动
Do not draw your weapons!
不要开枪
Ladies and gentlemen, I think we'll call that an evening...
各位,今晚就告一段落
Thank you, and good night.
谢谢大家,晚安
Juntao.
钟涛
Juntao!
I got something for you!
我有东西给你
I got something you want.
你要的东西
I got your bomb right here.
这是你的炸弹
Sweetheart.
女儿
Daddy!
爸爸
Hold on.
别去
Want to blow something up?
想炸死我们吗?
Come on.
来呀
Push the button. Come on.
按下去呀
Push the button.
快按呀
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
I'm playing. Play along.
我在唬他,一起唬他吧
Come on, push the button!
尽管按下去
Yeah, come on, push the button!
是啊,尽管按吧
Blow everybody up.
炸死大家最好
Yeah, blow everybody up!
对,把大家炸死
Push the goddamn button.
快按吧
按下去
You heard what she said.
你听到她的话
Come on!
快呀
Everybody excited about something blowing up
大家都好兴奋
and look at your little punk British ass.
你却怕得要命
Come on! Push the button!
快点,按下去
Deal with it, please.
搞定他
Where you going?
你上哪儿?
Cover the Consul!
保护领事
No, no.
不,不
It's okay. She's professional.
别怕,她是爆破专家
We must take the vest off.
一定要脱掉背心
Okay, give me a second.
等我一下子
Just give me a second.
再等一下
There's a trigger on this vest. It'll blow if I take it off.
背心有机关,脱掉就会爆炸
Haven't you done this before?
你没拆除过吗?
It's different in the practice room.
这跟演习不同
Everybody take cover.
快找掩护
We need more men down here!
请派人手支援
Say again! Dan, do you read me?
请重覆,你收到吗?
Need some help down here, damn it!
快派人来支援
"Roses are red"
玫瑰艳丽
"Violets are blue"
紫罗兰娇美
"Sugar is sweet"
糖果甜蜜
"And so are you"
你也一样
The remote can still set it off.
他能用摇控器引爆
Get rid of it.
快脱掉吧
She okay? Yes.
她没事吧? 没事
I know that ain't the bomb!
那不是炸弹吧?
Get that bomb away from me! Take the bomb outside!
离我远点,把炸弹拿出去
Take the bomb outside.
快把它拿出去
Juntao.
钟涛
Yeah, take it over to Juntao. Go to Juntao.
拿给钟涛,拿给他
You go this way. I go that way.
你走那儿,我走这儿
Go!
走吧
Don't shoot!
别开枪
Shit!
该死
Where you going?
你上哪儿?
Meet me on the roof.
到屋顶等我
Don't move, man.
不要动
Yeah.
好了
I been looking for your sweet and sour chicken ass.
我一直在找你这块咕老肉
Your boys ain't here. Where they at? You all alone.
你的手下都不在
I kill him.
我会杀死他的
Go ahead. I don't like him.
我讨厌他,尽管下手吧
Put your gun down.
把枪放下
Fight like a man.
我们单打独斗
What you say?
你说什么?
Fight like a man.
单打独斗
Fight like a man?
单打独斗?
All right. I'll kick your ass. Then I'll take your ass to jail.
好,我先扁你,再送你坐牢
All right, come on, put the gun down.
好了,把枪放下
Same time.
一起放下
Wipe yourself off, man. You dead.
擦一下,你死了
Thank you, God.
感谢上帝
Carter.
卡特
Oh, shit.
该死
You know he dead.
他死了
Carter.
卡特
Help! Do something!
救命啊,快想办法
Be cool, man! Hang on!
冷静点,撑着点
I can't hold on anymore!
我抓不住了
Hang on for about a hour! I'll get the ambulance! I'll be back!
再撑一小时,我去叫救护车
What the hell are you doing?
你在鬼扯什么?
Just hang on! I'll be right back!
撑着点,我马上回来
Carter.
卡特
I was just playing.
我只是开玩笑
Do something!
快想办法
I can't hold on anymore.
我撑不住了
Oh, shit.
糟糕
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢你,谢谢
Man, what the hell you doing?
你在干嘛?
I just being polite.
这是礼貌呀
Next time, be polite to my nuts.
下次别那么用力
I'm sorry.
对不起
Thank you.
谢谢你
Oh, shit.
可恶
Excuse me. Are you all right?
你没事吧?
I'm fine.
没事
I owe you everything.
我欠你很多
Only your friendship.
你只欠我一份友情
Look who's here.
看看这是谁
What took you so long?
你怎么现在才来?
I think this belongs to you.
这是你的
Thank you.
谢谢
You should come with me.
你应该跟我去
Get on the plane when you get off work. You fly for free.
下了班就搭免费飞机来
I'm a young black man trying to expand my horizons.
我这老黑能扩展你的视野
Travel a little bit. See the world.
环游世界、见见世面
What y'all doing? I'm through with y'all. I'm going on vacation.
干嘛?我要去度假
Now, hold on there.
先别急着走
We came by to tell you what a great job you did yesterday.
你昨天的表现太好了
And when you come back, there'll be an FBI badge waiting for you.
你回来就能当FBI干员
You serious?
真的吗?
Come on, man, don't be playing.
你不要骗我
I don't know what to say. It's like a dream come true.
我太感动了,我的梦想成真
I got a idea though.
我有个点子
Why don't y'all take that badge
把那些FBI徽章拿出来
and shove it up yoru ass? All up in your ass.
塞进你们的屁眼
I'm LAPD.
我是洛城警探
Bitch.
臭小子
First class, I like this. This is tight.
头等舱,棒呆了
Can I take your jacket, sir?
我帮你拿外套
My jacket? No, you can take this bag though.
不必了,帮我拿行李吧
How you doing? What's up?
你好,怎么样?
What's up, man? You ready to go?
怎么样?走了吧?
May I offer you some peanuts?
您要来点花生吗?
Thank you.
谢谢你
You are very beautiful.
你很美
Thank you very much.
谢谢你
You never told me you spoke Chinese.
你没说你会讲中文
I never told you I didn't. You assume I didn't.
我没说我不会,是你假设的
This is cool. Han's letting me go to Hong Kong with you.
酷毙了,老韩让我跟你去香港
I ain't had a vacation in 5 years.
五年来我没度过假
We can hang in my crib. I will show you my 'hood.
你住我的窝,我带你到处混
You can show me some Chinese girls.
带我找中国小妞
When I get there, I want a massage. I'll get buck-wild.
我要去按摩,狂欢作乐
No police work for two weeks... How long this flight?
享受两个礼拜,要飞多久?
Fifteen hours.
十五个钟头
Fifteen hours? What are we going to do for 15 hours?
十五个钟头?要做什么呀?
Hell, no.
我不要
Stewardess!
小姐
Stewardess, give me another seat!
小姐,我要换座位
Listen to me!
听我说
Stewardess!
小姐